hey gang Hatter here so like you I had
been seeing ads for this silen not
reusable silicone on Instagram and as a
longtime oyumaru Enthusiast my curiosity
was peaked my wife got me a bottle for
my birthday so that I could try it out
thanks honey first of all I love that
there's no mixing anything so you can't
really mess up any ratios secondly
there's supposedly no cure inhibition on
UV resin printed Parts because it sets
at a temperature instead of via a
chemical reaction and this is super
valuable to me because I like to 3D
print my masters this stuff sort of
smells like toothpaste to me but like a
fancy organic toothpaste named after
some guy's first name now my first test
part is going to be the reactor core
from the Gundam Wing no- grade 1 to 144
scale V8 that I've been working on now I
did this stuff in no favors I was barely
following the directions on the bottle I
don't have a vacuum chamber for
degassing to get those bubbles out and I
started with a really complex part in a
one piece mold this was inspired by
Robert tone the mold Meister now this
part has a ton of undercuts and huge
gaps that will need to be cut out later
which makes it a nightmare to work with
in this fashion no seriously I really
should have done a two-part mold after a
few hours in the fridge I was confident
enough to cut this thing
open the master part has some guides
that I tried to follow in order to keep
any seam lines on the resin copy hidden
on the back of the
part even after a botched slice job the
mold is still intact and ready for me to
try out some two-part
resin I am using the absolute cheapest
clear resin that I found on Amazon again
I am basically trying to make the cenut
[Music]
fail because the top spout is so small I
have to sort of pipe the resin into each
of the sides of the open mold in order
to fill it
up we're going to give it about 8 to 12
to set up before we crack it
open so now we remove our part and I got
to say I am impressed with the level of
detail captured it looks like maybe some
of the blue pigment leeched into the
resin but I'm going to be wiring this
thing up with LEDs so I don't really
mind the only major flaw in the part was
this air bubble that I caught when I was
filling the mold with resin but that's a
me problem I did tear the mold quite a
bit when removing the part but who cares
I can just remelt it and cast another
mold which is the main selling point of
this product so the final verdict this
is another fantastic tool to have in
your gumla Arsenal for making quick
copies of parts and accessories the
details it captured are far superior
than what you would get from an OU Maru
mold like I said there was a little
color stain on the copy but most of you
are going to be painting these parts
anyway the mold isn't particularly
durable after the First cast but again
the idea isn't that you're going to be
making one mold to last for hundreds of
castings this is for those oneandone
projects so that you can recycle CLE the
material and make more molds thank you
guys so much for watching and a special
thank you to my patrons for supporting
the wing Gundam rebuild project let me
know in the comments down below if you
guys have tried out any other new mold
making gumpla products recently until
next time I will catch you later
n